Guide to the Eldon Dedini Papers
The Ohio State University Billy Ireland Cartoon Library & Museum
Eldon Dedini Papers
1920-2005
The Ohio State University Billy Ireland Cartoon Library & Museum
Dedini, Eldon
150 linear feet (154 boxes)
This collection contains books, comic books, original art and papers of cartoonist, Eldon Dedini (1921-2006)
SPEC.CGA.ED
Biography of Eldon Dedini
Eldon Dedini was born on June 21, 1921. He grew up in rural California on a ranch in King City. Eldon knew from an early age that he wanted to be a cartoonist and received support from his family to pursue his dream. In high school he drew cartoons for two local newspapers without payment in order to gain experience. While at Salinas Junior College, he sold his first cartoon to Esquire. After graduation he furthered his art education at Chouinard Institute of Art in Los Angeles. He married classmate, painter Virginia Conroy after their graduation in 1944. They adopted son, Giulio in 1960. He began his career at Universal Studios and then as a storyboard writer for Disney and worked on films such as "Mickey and the Beanstalk." In 1946 the editor of Esquire recognized his potential and offered Dedini double his salary to work exclusively for the magazine, generating ideas for other cartoonists as well as creating cartoons himself. In 1950, Dedini began to submit cartoons to the New Yorker and soon became one the magazine's contract artists, which gave the publication first choice of cartoons. Hugh Hefner, the creator of Playboy, was a fan of Dedini's work and asked him for a few years to work for Playboy and was eventually able to convince him to join after Esquire was sold in 1959. Most issues of Playboy featured at least one full-page color cartoon beginning in 1959. Dedini continued to draw for Playboy and the New Yorker, as well as freelance for many other national publications until his death on January 12, 2006.
Dedini was recognized by the National Cartoonists Society as winner of Gag Cartoonist of the Year award in 1958, 1961, 1964, and 1988.
Eldon was also very active in giving back to his community. He was a founding member of the group that helped to restore Cannery Row to its former glory and continue its preservation. He also was an active volunteer for his church, All Saints Episcopal Church, creating the comic strip "Brother Larry" for the newsletter as well has helping out in the kitchen on Christmas. He passed away at age 84 on January 12, 2006.
Scope and Content
The collection was inventoried by Billy Ireland Cartoon Library & Museum staff in 2006, which produced a box level inventory. The collection was processed using the MPLP approach (More Product, Less Process). As such the physical arrangement of the collection was left in the order that it was originally packaged, while an intellectual order of the contents, organizing the collection into thirteen series, has been imposed. The corresponding box level information is included in the inventory guide, but note that the materials are loosely arranged in the boxes and represents the order of which Dedini originally stored his files at the Carmel, California home. This collection contains a variety of Dedini's work including original cartoon art from Playboy, The New Yorker, Esquire, and other national publications, advertising, book illustrations, and freelance work. It also contains his roughs and sketches, his research files, information on the professional and charitable organizations that he belonged to, correspondence, personal materials, and memorabilia.
Statement of Arrangement
This collection is broken into thirteen series. The first three series, Playboy, New Yorker, and Esquire have sub-series. More information on the contents can be found in the container list.
Series I: Playboy, 1974-2005
Sub-Series 1: Playboy Correspondence, 1999-2005, Undated
Sub-Series 2: Playboy Sketches and Roughs, 1970-2002
Series II: New Yorker, 1950-2005
Sub-Series 1: New Yorker Correspondence, 1953-2005
Sub-Series 2: New Yorker Sketches and Roughs, 1970-2002
Series III: Esquire, 1940-1964
Sub-Series 1: Esquire Correspondence, 1960-1964
Sub-Series 2: Esquire Sketches and Roughs, 1940-1965
Series IV: Advertising Illustrations, 1980s-2003, Undated
Series V: Book Illustrations, Undated
Series VI: Freelance Works, 1940-2005
Series VII: Sketches, Drawings, and Scrapbooks, 1950-2005
Series VIII: Original Art, Undated
Series IX: Research Files, 1950s-2000s, Undated
Series X: Professional and Charitable Organizations, 1960s-2005, Undated
Series XI: Correspondence, 1940-2000s
Series XII: Personal and Family Materials, 1921-2006, Undated
Series XIII: Memorabilia, 1920s-2000s, Undated
Separated Material
Original art by Eldon Dedini has been separated out and cataloged at the item level in the Original Art Database
Related Material
Works by Eldon Dedini have been cataloged in The Ohio State University Libraries catalog under "Dedini, Eldon." Books owned by Dedini, which often feature his illustrations have been cataloged under the title "Eldon Dedini Collection."Also available in the libraries catalog are published issues of magazines such as Esquire and the New Yorker with Dedini's works. Miscellaneous clippings about Dedini may be found in the library's biography file under his last name.
Restrictions on Access
There are no restrictions for materials in this collection.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Eldon Dedini, 2006. Later accessions to the collection were given by Giulio Dedini in 2007 and 2009.
Custodial History
The collection was assembled, owned, and maintained by Eldon Dedini.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Wit and humor, Pictorial; Magazine illustration; Advertising--illustrations; Illustration of books
Persons:
Dedini, Eldon, 1921-2006
Organizations/Corporations:
Playboy (Chicago, Ill.); New Yorker (New York, N.Y.: 1925); Esquire (New York, N.Y.)
Places:
Carmel (Calif.)
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Series I. Playboy, 1954-2005
  This series contains information on Dedini's work for Playboy. It is further divided into two sub-series: Correspondence and Sketches and Roughs. The first sub-series includes letter from Playboy Cartoon editor, Michelle Urry, and magazine founder Hugh Hefner. The second sub-series contains sketches and roughs of cartoons drawn for the publication.
  - Sub-Series 1. Playboy Correspondence, 1999-2005, Undated
    - Playboy Foreign Language Edition Payments, 1970s (Box ED 1, Folder 1)
    - Playboy - Correspondence with Hugh Hefner and Michelle Urry (9 Folders), 1954-2005 (Box ED 1, Folder 2-10)
    - PEI, Undated (Box ED 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence with Editors and Roughs, 2005 (Box ED 93, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence and Index of Cartoons Sold to Playboy (2 Folders), 1974-2005 (Box ED 93, Folder 4-5)
    - Playboy Correspondence with Michelle Urry, 2005-2006 (Box ED 93, Folder 7)
    - Playboy Holiday Greeting Cards from Michelle Urry, Undated (Box ED 93, Folder 8)
  - Sub-Series 2. Playboy sketches and roughs, 1970-2002
    - Playboy Future Cartoons to Sell, Undated (Box ED 1, Folder 12)
    - Playboy X-Mas, 1986 (Box ED 1, Folder 12)
    - Playboy to Go Now-Notes Done for Xmas/New Year 2000 (Box ED 1, Folder 14)
    - Playboy-Christmas/New Year 1994 (Box ED 1, Folder 15)
    - Playboy, 1999 (Box ED 1, Folder 16)
    - Playboy Now, Undated (Box ED 1, Folder 17)
    - Playboy Contemporary Culture Scenes (roughs/research notes), Undated (Box ED 1, Folder 18)
    - Playboy September (roughs), 2000 (Box ED 1, Folder 19)
    - Playboy to-go (roughs/clippings), Undated (Box ED 1, Folder 20)
    - Playboy to-go not yet (roughs/clippings), Undated (Box ED 1, Folder 21)
    - Playboy (rework roughs), March 1993 (Box ED 1, Folder 22)
    - Playboy Ads/Greeting Cards, Undated (Box ED 1, Folder 23)
    - Playboy Fantasy Panels and Articles, Undated (Box ED 1, Folder 24)
    - Playboy and New Yorker Mix (rough of Krazy Kat, Ignatz Mouse, Mickey Mouse), Undated (Box ED 1, Folder 25)
    - Playboy roughs, 1987 (Box ED 1, Folder 26)
    - Playboy Miscellaneous, Undated (Box ED 1, Folder 27)
    - Playboy Doodles, April 1990 (Box ED 1, Folder 28)
    - Playboy Doodles Classic Scenes, Undated (Box ED 1, Folder 29)
    - Playboy Doodles Other (includes roughs of Dick Tracy), 1970-1990 (Box ED 1, Folder 30)
    - Parody (includes roughs of Charlie Brown cartoon), Undated (Box ED 1, Folder 31)
    - Playboy Wine Spread, Undated (Box ED 2, Folder 1)
    - Playboy roughs, 1978 (Box ED 2, Folder 2)
    - Playboy roughs, 1981 (Box ED 2, Folder 3)
    - Playboy roughs, 1988 (Box ED 2, Folder 4)
    - Playboy roughs, 1984-1985 (Box ED 2, Folder 5)
    - Playboy roughs and xeroxes (14 Folders), 1988-2002 (Box ED 2, Folder 6-19)
    - Playboy, 1974-1976 (Box ED 2, Folder 20)
    - Playboy Roughs (3 Folders), 1982 (Box ED 2, Folder 21-23)
    - Early Playboy Roughs (2 Folders), Undated (Box ED 2, Folder 24-25)
    - Playboy Roughs, 2003 (Box ED 2, Folder 26)
    - Playboy Roughs and Xeroxes, 2004 (Box ED 2, Folder 27)
    - Playboy Roughs and Xeroxes, 2005 (Box ED 2, Folder 28)
    - Roughs to Michelle Urry, Special Gags, Home and Family Ideas, 1993 (Box ED 2, Folder 29)
    - Playboy Xmas and New Years Roughs, Undated (Box ED 2, Folder 30)
    - Playboy Roughs, Xmas early notes, Worth a Thought, Undated (Box ED 2, Folder 31)
    - Playboy Xmas, 1995 (Box ED 2, Folder 32)
    - Playboy Christmas Roughs, 1990 (Box ED 2, Folder 33)
    - Playboy Roughs (some in color), 1988-1998 (Box ED 3, Folder 1)
    - Playboy Roughs, 2000 (Box ED 3, Folder 2)
    - Playboy Xmas (some in color), Undated (Box ED 3, Folder 3)
    - Playboy Roughs in color, 1988 (Box ED 3, Folder 4)
    - Xmas, 1991 (Box ED 3, Folder 5)
    - Typed Captions, Undated (Box ED 93, Folder 3)
    - Cartoons Sold to Playboy, New Yorker, and Others (2 Folders), 1975-1999 (Box ED 93, Folder 9-10)
    - "Okayed" Playboy, 2004-2005 (Box ED 93, Folder 6)
- Series II. The New Yorker, 1950-2005
  This series contains information on his work for the New Yorker. It is further divided into two sub-series: Correspondence and Sketches and Roughs. The first sub-series includes correspondence with the magazine's editors. The second sub-series contains sketches and roughs of cartoons drawn for the publication.
  - Sub-Series 1. The New Yorker Correspondence, 1953-2005, Undated
    - R.C. Harvey New Yorker, Undated (Box ED 3, Folder 6)
    - New Yorker Correspondence (Deadlines and Submissions), Undated (Box ED 3, Folder 7)
    - Lee Lorenz Correspondence- New Yorker, Undated (Box ED 3, Folder 8)
    - William Shawn Correspondence- New Yorker), Undated (Box ED 3, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence-Transition William Shawn, Undated (Box ED 3, Folder 10)
    - Lee Lorenz- New Yorker Correspondence, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Index New Yorker, Undated (Box ED 3, Folder 12)
    - New Yorker Correspondence and Contract (5 Folders), 1949-1950s, 160-1961, 1964-1968 (Box ED 3, Folder 13-17)
    - AIG The New Yorker, 1990s (Box ED 3, Folder 18)
    - Jim Geraghty and Barbra Nicholls Correspondence-New Yorker, 1971-1973 (Box ED 3, Folder 19)
    - Lee Lorenz, 1973-1979 (Box ED 3, Folder 20)
    - New Yorker, 2001-2005 (Box ED 3, Folder 21)
    - Nichols Gallery, New Yorker 60 Year Retrospective, 1986 (Box ED 3, Folder 22)
    - New Yorker sales, records, or letters of Where Dedini Cartoons have been reprinted, 1970s-1980s (Box ED 3, Folder 23)
    - New Yorker Correspondence and Records (3 Folders), 1953-1954, 1957-1958, 1960 (Box ED 3, Folder 24-26)
    - New Yorker Jackie O Correspondence, Undated (Box ED 3, Folder 25)
    - David Smart and Jim Geraghty Transition, 1950-1951 (Box ED 3, Folder 27)
    - New Yorker Records of all cartoons published in New Yorker (and A Much, Much Better World notes), 1950s-1980s (Box ED 4, Folder 1)
    - New Yorker Employee Retirement Annuities, 1980 (Box ED 93, Folder 11)
    - Cards listing cartoons sold to New Yorker and Playboy, 1976-1997 (Box ED 93, Folder 12)
  - Sub-Series 2. The New Yorker sketches and roughs, 1970-2002, Undated
    - New Yorker roughs, 1987 (Box ED 4, Folder 2)
    - New Yorker roughs (6 Folders), 1994-1998 (Box ED 4, Folder 3-8)
    - New Yorker random years and numbers, Undated (Box ED 4, Folder 9)
    - New Yorker mixed years and 3000 numbers, Undated (Box ED 4, Folder 10)
    - New Yorker Doodles and Roughs, include Eartha Kitt caricature, Undated (Box ED 4, Folder 11)
    - New Yorker roughs, dog-cat jokes, Undated (Box ED 4, Folder 12)
    - New Yorker grab bag roughs, Undated (Box ED 4, Folder 13)
    - New Yorker early roughs, 1950s-1960s (Box ED 4, Folder 14)
    - New Yorker Roughs (includes roughs from May 1985), March 1983 (Box ED 4, Folder 15)
    - Roughs, September 1983 (Box ED 4, Folder 16)
    - Roughs, February 1984 (Box ED 4, Folder 17)
    - Roughs, May- June 1985 (Box ED 4, Folder 18)
    - Roughs, July 1985 (Box ED 4, Folder 19)
    - Roughs, October 1985 (Box ED 4, Folder 20)
    - Roughs, June 1986 (Box ED 4, Folder 21)
    - Roughs, June- July 1986 (Box ED 4, Folder 22)
    - Roughs, February- March 1989 (Box ED 4, Folder 23)
    - New Yorker Roughs to-go, Undated (Box ED 4, Folder 24)
    - New Yorker, next batch to go..., Undated (Box ED 4, Folder 25)
    - New Yorker roughs, Undated (Box ED 4, Folder 26-27)
    - New Yorker Roughs, 1994-1997, Undated (Box ED 4, Folder 28)
    - New Yorker Clippings, Undated (Box ED 5, Folder 1)
    - Scenes/New Yorker, Undated (Box ED 5, Folder 2)
    - New Yorker Roughs, April- June 1986 (Box ED 5, Folder 5-7)
    - New Yorker Roughs, January- February 1986 (Box ED 5, Folder 5)
    - New Yorker Roughs, Undated (Box ED 5, Folder 6-7)
    - New Yorker Ready-to-Send, Undated (Box ED 5, Folder 8)
    - New Yorker Roughs and New York Scenes, Undated (Box ED 5, Folder 9)
    - New Yorker Roughs (2 Folders), Undated (Box ED 5, Folder 11-12)
    - New Yorker Roughs, 1993 (Box ED 5, Folder 10)
    - New Yorker resend, rework (some good thoughts), Undated (Box ED 5, Folder 13)
    - New Yorker Doodles, Undated (Box ED 5, Folder 14)
    - New Yorker: Idea once submitted; maybe worth a re-do, Undated (Box ED 5, Folder 15)
    - New Yorker Ready-to-go now, Undated (Box ED 5, Folder 16)
    - New Yorker to-go now, Undated (Box ED 83, Folder 1)
    - New Yorker Good Pics (roughs), Undated (Box ED 5, Folder 17)
    - New Yorker Roughs, 1991 (Box ED 5, Folder 18)
    - New Yorker Roughs, 1990 (Box ED 5, Folder 19)
    - New Yorker Roughs, 1989 (Box ED 5, Folder 20)
    - New Yorker Notes, 1970s-1980s (Box ED 5, Folder 21)
    - New Yorker Out of Number Sequence, Undated (Box ED 5, Folder 22)
    - New Yorker jokes concerning end of communism, 1980s-1990s (Box ED 5, Folder 23)
    - New Yorker Roughs (2 Folders), Undated (Box ED 5, Folder 24-25)
    - New Yorker Roughs, September- October 1994 (Box ED 5, Folder 26)
    - New Yorker Roughs Now, May 1995 (Box ED 5, Folder 27)
    - New Yorker Roughs, March 1992 (Box ED 5, Folder 28)
    - Gags/Roughs, 1969-1971 (Box ED 5, Folder 29)
    - New Yorker to go, Undated (Box ED 5, Folder 30)
    - New Yorker Roughs March 1982 and Notes from the 1970s-1980s, 1970s-1980s, March 1982 (Box ED 5, Folder 31)
    - In the works, New Yorker, February- March 2002 (Box ED 6, Folder 1)
    - New Yorker/Next Time, Undated (Box ED 6, Folder 2)
    - New Yorker/Good Scenes in the Works, Undated (Box ED 6, Folder 3)
    - New Yorker Doodles, July 1990 (Box ED 6, Folder 4)
    - Full Page New Yorker Possibilities, Undated (Box ED 6, Folder 5)
    - New Yorker Cartoons-Dates of Publication, Undated (Box ED 6, Folder 6)
    - Lenin Roughs sent to New Yorker, Undated (Box ED 6, Folder 7)
    - Unfinished roughs in the works, Undated (Box ED 6, Folder 8)
    - New Yorker Roughs- Fiddle with these and find others, Undated (Box ED 6, Folder 9)
    - New Yorker new scenes- create a world!, Undated (Box ED 6, Folder 10)
    - Fantasies, Undated (Box ED 6, Folder 11)
    - Rework scenes- best saved for future thoughts and notes, 1979 (Box ED 6, Folder 12)
    - New Yorker Roughs, August- September 1987 (Box ED 6, Folder 13)
    - Roughs about to-go, 1999 (Box ED 6, Folder 14)
    - In the works, 1999 (Box ED 6, Folder 15)
    - New Yorker to-go, Undated (Box ED 6, Folder 16)
    - New Yorker Now, Undated (Box ED 6, Folder 17)
    - New Yorker to-go next, Undated (Box ED 6, Folder 18)
    - New Yorker Roughs (17 Folders), 1973-1985 (Box ED 6, Folder 19-35)
    - New Yorker Roughs (6 Folders), 1985-1988 (Box ED 7, Folder 1-6)
    - New Yorker Covers, Undated (Box ED 7, Folder 7)
    - Roughs, 2003-2004 (Box ED 7, Folder 8-9)
    - Gags and roughs/ Lee Lorenz, Undated (Box ED 7, Folder 10)
    - New Yorker Covers Roughs, 1990s (Box ED 7, Folder 11)
    - Cover ideas, 1994-1997, Undated (Box ED 7, Folder 12)
    - Cover roughs, Undated (Box ED 7, Folder 13)
    - Cover notes, Undated (Box ED 7, Folder 14)
    - Early cover notes, Undated (Box ED 7, Folder 15)
    - Notes and correspondence, Undated (Box ED 7, Folder 16)
    - New Yorker Cover notes and better possibilities, Undated (Box ED 7, Folder 17)
    - Ink Panels, Undated (Box ED 7, Folder 18)
    - New Yorker Roughs, April 1982 (Box ED 7, Folder 19)
    - Roughs, September 1984 (Box ED 7, Folder 20)
    - Roughs and Words, May 1990- June 1991 (Box ED 7, Folder 21)
    - New Yorker Gag notes, March to November, 1991 (Box ED 7, Folder 22)
    - New Yorker Xmas, 1991 (Box ED 7, Folder 23)
    - New Yorker, January- February 1992 (Box ED 7, Folder 24)
    - New Yorker, February- March 1992 (Box ED 7, Folder 25)
    - New Yorker Roughs to Tina Brown (2 Folders), 1992 (Box ED 7, Folder 26-27)
    - New Yorker roughs to go, 1989 (Box ED 7, Folder 28)
    - New Yorker roughs: check this out!, Undated (Box ED 7, Folder 29)
    - New Yorker Roughs Current, Undated (Box ED 7, Folder 30)
    - New Yorker Rough and Gags, 1974, 1977, 1982, 1988, Undated (Box ED 7, Folder 31)
    - New Yorker Roughs, 1999 (Box ED 8, Folder 28)
    - New Yorker Cover sizes, Undated (Box ED 11, Folder 1)
    - New Yorker Covers and Correspondence with Francoise Mouly, 2000-2001 (Box ED 11, Folder 2)
    - New Yorker Cover Prints (some sent), Undated (Box ED 11, Folder 3)
    - New Yorker Cover ideas, notes, roughs, and sketches, Undated (Box ED 11, Folder 4)
    - New Yorker Roughs (3 Folders), 2000 (Box ED 12, Folder 1-3)
    - New Yorker in the works, sizes and logos, Undated (Box ED 20, Folder 1)
    - New Yorker Roughs, January- February 1983 (Box ED 23, Folder 1)
    - New Yorker Roughs, May 1983 (Box ED 23, Folder 2)
    - New Yorker Roughs, November 1983 (Box ED 23, Folder 3)
    - New Yorker Roughs, February- March, 1986 (Box ED 23, Folder 4)
    - New Yorker Gag Notes, December 1990 (Box ED 23, Folder 5)
    - New Yorker Roughs Reworks, March- April 1993 (Box ED 23, Folder 6)
    - New Yorker Roughs, August 1993 (Box ED 23, Folder 7)
    - New Yorker Roughs and Captions, now, Undated (Box ED 23, Folder 8)
    - New Yorker Spread Ideas (some Playboy), Undated (Box ED 23, Folder 9)
    - New Yorker Roughs and Caption Ideas, January 1999 (Box ED 23, Folder 10)
    - New Yorker Roughs, Now, Undated (Box ED 23, Folder 11)
    - New Yorker Gags, Early Notes (some still funny?), Undated (Box ED 23, Folder 12)
    - New Yorker Ideas and doodles, Undated (Box ED 23, Folder 13)
    - Spreads New Yorker (some Playboy), Undated (Box ED 23, Folder 14)
    - New Yorker Roughs and Clippings, December 1993 (Box ED 23, Folder 15)
    - New Yorker Notes (Remember! Ideas with an edge! No white bread), January 1993 (Box ED 23, Folder 16)
    - New Yorker Doodles, Undated (Box ED 43, Folder 13)
    - New Yorker (roughs), Undated (Box ED 83, Folder 16)
    - New Yorker Roughs, 1993 (Box ED 83, Folder 4)
    - New Yorker Ideas Submitted (worth re-do), Undated (Box ED 83, Folder 5)
    - New Yorker (roughs), Undated (Box ED 83, Folder 17)
- Series III. Esquire, 1940-1965
  This series contains information on his work for Esquire. It is further divided into two sub-series: Correspondence and Sketches and Roughs. The first sub-series includes correspondence with the magazine's editors. The second sub-series contains sketches and roughs of cartoons drawn for the publication.
  - Sub-Series 1. Esquire Correspondence, 1960-1964
    - Correspondence with Esquire, 1946-1947 (Box ED 8, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence (2 Folders), 1948-1949 (Box ED 8, Folder 2-3)
    - Correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box ED 8, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1950-1952 (Box ED 8, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, includes reply from David A. Smart regarding political cartoon suggestions from Esquire, 1950-1952, 1954 (Box ED 8, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Jerry Beatty, Cartoon Editor, 1960-1964 (Box ED 8, Folder 7)
  - Sub-Series 2. Esquire sketches and roughs, 1940-1965
    - Finishes for others, roughs and pen sketches, Undated (Box ED 8, Folder 8)
    - Early Esquire Roughs and Notes [of doubtful value other than sentimental- ED note] (2 Folders), Undated (Box ED 8, Folder 9-10)
    - Very Early Esquire-New Yorker Panel Experiments, Pen Sketches, 1940-1959 (Box ED 8, Folder 11)
    - Harem ideas done for Esquire and E. Sims Campbell, 1940s-1950s (Box ED 8, Folder 12)
    - Early Esquire Roughs-Okayed Gags, Undated (Box ED 8, Folder 13)
    - Coronet-Esquire Cover Ideas, Done for Oscar Dystel, Undated (Box ED 8, Folder 14)
    - Esquire Calendars, Undated (Box ED 9)
    - Esquire Clippings, Undated (Box ED 9, Folder 1)
    - Dedini clippings mounted on paper (5 Folders), 1946-1950 (Box ED 9, Folder 2-7)
- Series IV. Advertising Illustrations, 1980s-2003, Undated
  This series contains advertising work that Dedini created for various companies. There is a significant amount of work for Mann Packing beginning in the 1980s, for which he created the character Broccoli Wokly. Although many materials in the series are undated it is presumed they were created throughout Dedini's career, 1940s-2000s.
  - Lintas- Valen, Undated (Box ED 8, Folder 15)
  - Portola (Grove-Portola Savings), Undated (Box ED 8, Folder 16)
  - Del Monte, 1980 (Box ED 8, Folder 17)
  - Valen-other (2 folders), 1979-1980, 1990 (Box ED 8, Folder 18-19)
  - Penn Tennis, Undated (Box ED 8, Folder 20)
  - SRDS, Undated (Box ED 8, Folder 21)
  - Advertising- Valen, RQ & W, Kenyon, and Eckham, 1960s-1970s (Box ED 8, Folder 22)
  - Kennedy Associates NYC, Undated (Box ED 8, Folder 23)
  - John Temple, Undated (Box ED 8, Folder 24)
  - Firestone, Undated (Box ED 8, Folder 25)
  - Barnyard, Undated (Box ED 8, Folder 27)
  - Tear sheets of Mann Packing Ads, Undated (Box ED 10, Folder 1)
  - Mann Packing Ad Prints, 1987 (Box ED 10, Folder 2)
  - Original artwork for Mann Packing, Undated (Box ED 10, Folder 3)
  - Broccoli Wokly Placemats, 1993 (Box ED 10, Folder 4)
  - Mann Packing Broccoli Power, mylar balloon, Undated (Box ED 10, Folder 5)
  - Broccoli Wokly Vegetable Stand coloring books with pencils, sharpener, and stickers, 1994 (Box ED 10, Folder 6)
  - Mann Packing, Broccoli Puzzle "Good Schools Make Good Citizens...Suport Your Local Schools", Undated (Box ED 10, Folder 7)
  - Advertising, Smith-Greenland, Undated (Box ED 10)
  - Stu Heinicke, Undated (Box ED 11, Folder 6)
  - Ed Mitchell, NCCHA Calendar, 1987 (Box ED 11, Folder 5)
  - SPCA, Undated (Box ED 11, Folder 7)
  - All Saints Day School Rites of Spring, ca.1990s (Box ED 11, Folder 8)
  - All Saints Flyers- Vacation Bible School, 1991 (Box ED 11, Folder 9)
  - Our Town play posters for Outdoor Forest Theater in Carmel, 1988 (Box ED 11, Folder 10)
  - Fukuko Yorifuji, Undated (Box ED 11, Folder 11)
  - Lifetree Software, Undated (Box ED 11, Folder 12)
  - Stidolph Marriott, Undated (Box ED 11, Folder 13)
  - Rauh, Good, Darlo, and Barnes, Undated (Box ED 11, Folder 14)